Hello everyone and welcome back.So,in this video,
大家好 欢迎回来 在这个视频中
I'm going to be showing you how you actually build neural networks with PyTorch.
我将演示如何使用 PyTorch 构建神经网络
At the end of this notebook which I'll provide for
在此 notebook 的结尾 你将自己构建一个神经网络
you you'll build your own neural network.
我会提供此 notebook
So, let's get started.
我们开始吧
So, the first step we import things like Normal,
首先像往常一样导入库
to import PyTorch we do import torch.
要导入 PyTorch 输入 import torch
We're also going to import this package called
还将导入这个软件包 称为 torchvision
torchvision which is associated with PyTorch
它与 PyTorch 相关
and it allows us to download and use some existing datasets.
使我们能够下载并使用一些现有的数据集
The dataset that we're going to use for this is called MNIST.
在此视频中 我们将使用的数据集称为 MNIST
The MNIST dataset is just a bunch of images of hand drawn digits.
MNIST 数据集是一堆手写数字的图像
So, 0 through 9,
从 0 到 9
this dataset is used to train a network or other machine learning models
此数据集用于训练网络或其他机器学习模型
such they can classify the images into those details, right?
使它们能够将图像分类为数字
So then an image that shows at eight will be classified as the digit 8.
显示 8 的图像将被分类为数字 8
That's what we'll be using for this example.
我们将在此示例中使用该数据集
So, here I'm using torchvision to download and load the training data.
我使用 torchvision 下载并加载训练数据
So, this is the MNIST dataset that we can grab and put it into the trainset.
这是我们可以获取并放入 trainset 的 MNIST 数据集
So here I'm saying download equals true,
在这里输入 download=True
so if it doesn't exist on disk already,
如果磁盘上没有该数据集
then it will download it for us.
它将为我们下载该数据集
I'm also providing a transform.
在这里提供转换
So, what this does is it basically reads in these images and then applies
它的作用是读取这些图像
these transforms to give us our dataset that we feed into our network.
然后应用这些转换 生成传入网络的数据集
So, as it transform it looks like this so basically the first thing we do is
看起来这样
transform these images into a PyTorch tensor and then we normalize them.
首先将这些图像转换为 PyTorch 张量 然后标准化
So, what normalizing means in this case is that we want
在此示例中 标准化是指
to take our images which are grayscale images and each value,
对这些灰阶图像进行处理
each pixel is a float from zero to one but we actually
每个像素值是从 0 到 1 的浮点数
want our pixels to be from negative one to one.
但是我们希望像素值是从 -1 到 1
So, this is what this does is it subtracts 0.5,
这部分代码的作用是减 0.5
so this is the mean,
这是均值
so it will subtract from each color chamber,
从每个颜色通道 即每个像素减去 0.5
from each pixel, and then it's going to divide by 0.5.
然后除以 0.5
So, what this does is it moves this range of zero to one to
这部分的作用是将从 0 到 1 的范围
negative half to one half and then you divide by 0.5 or you multiply it by two,
变成从 -0.5 到 0.5 然后除以 0.5 或乘以 2
so that stretches out the variance to minus one to one.
使方差范围扩展为 -1 到 1
So, this just makes it easier for our neural networks to learn and you'll
这样使神经网络更容易学习
pretty much always want to normalize your data going into a neural network.
几乎每次将数据传入神经网络之前 都需要标准化数据
The other thing to note is that,
需要注意的另一点是
here I've set a batch size of 64.
我将批次大小设为 64
So, that basically means when we get our data out of trainloader here,
意思是当我们从 trainloader 获取数据时
is going to give us 64 images at a time.
每次将获得 64 张图像
Okay. So let me go and load this,
加载这个 然后加载数据
then load our data and now we can see what one of these images looks like.
现在可以看看其中一张图像的样貌了
So, here is one example and this is number seven.
这是一个示例 是一个数字 7
So this is just a hand-drawn digit that we
这是一个手写数字
are going to be classifying with our neural network.
我们将用神经网络对其进行分类
So, here is the network that we'll be building as example with MNIST.
我们将用 MNIST 构建这个示例网络
So,MNIST, the images are 28 by 28,
对于 MNIST 图像是 28 x 28
and so what we actually want to do is transform them
我们需要将它们转换为
into a vector that's 28 times 28 units long.
长度为 28 x 28 的向量
So 784, which is 28 times 28.
即 28 x 28=784
So this is the size of our input layer.
这是输入层的大小
So we're going to take our images, we convert them into
我们将接受图像 将它们转换为向量
a vector and then pass them in here as our inputs.
然后在这里作为输入传入网络中
We're going to use two hidden layers,
我们将使用两个隐藏层
the first with 128 units and the second was 64 units,
第一个有 128 个单元 第二个有 64 个单元
this is going to go to an output layer with 10 units.
这个将是输出层 有 10 个单元
This output layer has 10 units because we want
这个输出层有 10 个单元
to classify these digits and there's 10 of them, right?
因为我们想要分类这些数字 共有 10 个数字
So this one correspond to the digit 0,1,2 and so on.
这个对应数字 0 对应 1 2 等等
Here the number of units in each of these hidden layers and
每个隐藏层的单元数量
the number of hidden layers you actually use is somewhat arbitrary.
以及隐藏层的数量是不定的
In general, the more units you have on a layer and the more layers you have,
通常 层级中的单元越多 层级越多
the better your network will be able to fit the data.
网络就越能拟合数据
The large part of training neural networks is actually finding
训练神经网络的一大部分工作是
the best number of units and the best number of layers to using your network.
确定最佳单元数量和最佳层级数量
For activation functions, for the hidden layers
对于激活函数来说
are going to be using relus and for the output,
隐藏层将使用 ReLU
we're going to be using softmax.
输出层将使用 softmax
So, remember that softmax actually takes
softmax 接受这些输出单元的值
the values of these output units and transforms them into a probability distribution.
并将它们转换为概率分布
So, what that means is that it actually squishes
它会将所有这些值压扁到 0 和 1 之间
all these values between zero and one but then divides by the total things,
然后除以所有值的和
so, if you sum up the values for each of these units it equals one.
如果将每个单元的值相加 会等于 1
So, this is a discrete probability distribution that gives us
这是一个离散概率分布
the probability that whatever our input is it belongs to this class.
表示输入属于这个类别的概率
And to train this network,
要训练此网络
we're going to need a loss and so we're using a cross entropy loss.
我们需要一个损失函数 我们将使用交叉熵损失函数
What this does is compare the probability,
它的作用是
like the prediction from the softmax layer with
将 softmax 层的概率或预测
the true category and then you can use the difference,
与真实类别进行比较 然后使用二者之差（即损失）
that loss there to update the weights in your network.
更新网络中的权重
Okay, so it's time to build this network.
开始构建网络
So, firstly, we need to import a few modules from PyTorch.
首先 我们需要从 PyTorch 导入一些模块
So, from torch import nn,
输入 from torch import nn
this is like neural network functions.
它是神经网络函数
We can also import functional as F. So,
然后输入 import torch.nn.functional as F
this is more functions that are
有更多专门针对神经网络的函数
specifically around neural networks and this is just like a functional form of them.
这是这些函数的函数形式
With those imported, we can start building our network.
导入这些内容后 可以开始构建网络了
So, the kind of general,
在 PyTorch 中的基本方式是
most basic way you do this in PyTorch is by creating a class.
创建一个类
It doesn't really matter because those class network that is subclass from nn.Module.
并不重要 因为这个类 Network 是 nn.Module 的子类
Then in the init function,
然后在 init 函数中
you first need to call super.
首先需要调用 super()
So, basically what super does is
super() 的作用是
a calls functions or attributes of whatever class that this is subclassing from.
调用此子类所继承的类的函数或属性
So, what this line is going to do is it is actually going to call
这行代码的作用是
the init method of an nn.Module.
调用 nn.Module 的 init 方法
So that done, we're going to define the layers we are using,
完成后 我们将定义要使用的层级
the operations that will define the architecture of our neural network.
定义神经网络架构的运算
To do this, we'll call it self.fc,
为此 我们将称之为 self.fc1
so a fully connected layer.
表示全连接层
So fc is linear.
fc 是线性的
So this is, if you look at this,
看看这里的解释
this is applies that linear transformation to an incoming data.
它会向输入数据应用线性转换
So, this we need to put in our input,
我们需要在里面设定输入大小
size, and then the output size.
然后设定输出大小
So, we know that we have 784 units in
我们的输入层有 784 个单元
our input layer and we want our first hidden layer to be 128 units.
我们希望第一个隐藏层有 128 个单元
And for the second layer we can do something similar, 128 to 64.
第二个层级相似 128 到 64
Then the output layer call fc3.
输出层称为 fc3
So, this is going from 64 to 10.
从 64 到 10
That's pretty much all the operations that we need to define in this part.
这些差不多就是在这部分需要定义的所有运算
So, to get this to work as a neural network,
要使这个成为神经网络
we need to define a forward function.
我们需要定义 forward 函数
So, all PyTorch networks that you
从 nn.Module 构建的所有 PyTorch 网络
build from nn.Module need to have this forward function.
必须具有这个 forward 函数
So, what this is expecting is that x is a PyTorch tensor and
该函数要求 x 是一个 PyTorch 张量
then what you're going to do is basically just pass this tensor
你将这个张量传入每个层级
through each of your layers in each of your operations.
即传入每个运算
So for example, to do the first layer, so self.fc1 x.
例如 要传入第一层级 输入 self.fc1(x)
So, this is passing the tensor x through our first layer,
将张量 x 传入第一层级
through this first linear operation and that gives us another tensor.
传入这个线性运算 生成另一个张量
Then we can take that tensor and put
对该张量应用 ReLu 激活函数
the relu activation function on it and then go to the next one.
然后进入另一层级
So this kind of keep going like this.
差不多就是这么持续下去
Finally we do our softmax function.
最终 定义 softmax 函数
So,here we actually need to define the dimension that
我们需要定义
we want to calculate the softmax across.
计算 softmax 所在的维度
So, if you remember earlier I said that our images are actually going
之前我提到 图像将批次处理
to be batches and there's going to be 64 different images per batch,
每批将有 64 张不同的图像
and the way that looks with the tensor size is at the batch size is first.
对于张量大小来说 批次大小是第一个
So, that would be dimension zero.
即维度 0
Then our actual vector that we're passing through the network is the second dimension.
传入网络的实际向量是第二个维度
So, this tensor here is going to end up being 64 which is the batch size by 10.
这个张量最终将是 64x10 64 是批次大小
So, we actually want to take our softmax across the dimension that is has 10 values,
softmax 所在的维度有 10 个值
and so that's dimension one here.
因此这里是维度 1
And finally, you just return this.
最后输入 return x
So, we can create our model,
可以像这样创建模型了 创建网络了
our network like this and then see what it looks like.
看看结果如何
So, this basically will just tell us like all these modules,
这里显示的是我们在 init 函数中
these operations that we registered in the init function.
注册的这些模块 这些运算
So, we create these linear operations, these linear transformations.
我们创建了这些线性运算 这些线性转换
The weights and biases are automatically created for us.
系统自动为我们创建了权重和偏差
So, we can see that with model.fc1.weight, and I'll print this out.
输出 model.fc1.weight
Then also print fc1.bias.
然后还输出 fc1.bias
So, we can see we have these parameters
可以看到这些参数
here that have automatically been created and initialized for us.
系统自动为我们创建并初始化了这些参数
So, if we want to go in and reinitialize these parameters in bias in weights,
如果我们想重新初始化这些参数 这些偏差和权重
then we can get to our bias like this bias.
可以这样获得偏差
Then to get the underlying data,
然后获得底层数据
you say.data and now we can fill it in place with zeros.
输入 .data 并用 0 填充
So, now our bias that's attached to this linear operation in
现在 与第一个全连接层中的线性运算
the first fully connected layer is filled with zeros.
相关的偏差被 0 填充
Similarly, you can look at your weights.data,
同样 可以查看权重 输入 .data
and suppose we want to do a normal distribution.
假设我们想要获得正态分布
So, we want to initialize these random weights
我们想要用正态分布初始化这些随机权重
with a normal distribution with a standard deviation of 0.01.
标准偏差为 0.01
There we go. So, it's really convenient because basically
搞定 很方便
the bias and weight matrices are always available to you in your model.
因为始终可以在模型中查看偏差和权重指标
So, you just do model.whatever layer,
只需输入 model. 然后是任何层级名称
whatever operation and then.weight and that you can get your weights out.
任何运算 然后是 .weight 获得权重
Now that we have a network, I'm going to pass
我们已经有了一个网络
some data through it and see what it looks like.
我将传入一些数据 看看效果如何
We get our data from the train loader and what it does is it
从 trainloader 获取数据
returns images and then labels for each of those images.
它会返回图像和每个图像的标签
So, labels are the categories that the images belong to.
标签是指图像所属的类别
So, if there's an image of a zero then the label is zero,
如果图像是 0 则标签是 0
if there's an image of a five the label is five and so on.
如果图像是 5 则标签是 5 等等
So, we do is we call next iter trainloader.
调用 next(iter(trainloader))
So, train loader returns a generator.
trainloader 返回一个生成器
To make it something that you can actually iterate over,
要使其变成可以遍历的数据
you do iter and to get the first value of it, you do next.
调用 iter 要获得第一个值 调用 next
So, basically every time you call next on this,
每次调用 next
it's going to give you the next batch in your training data.
它都会返回训练数据中的下个批次
With images, we actually need to resize them now because remember they
对于图像 我们需要调整图像尺寸
come as 28 by 28 images and we need to make them a 784 long vector.
因为它们是 28 x 28 图像 我们需要使其变成 784 长的向量
So, say images.resize our batch size.
输入 images.resize 这是批次大小
This is like the number of color channels for instance and then 784.
这是颜色通道 然后输入 784
A somewhat better way to do this is if you actually pass in
更好的处理方式是
the batch size that you get from the images tensor itself.
传入从图像张量本身获取的批次大小
So, this is the first element of the shape.
这是 shape 的第一个元素
You won't do this because a lot of times you don't actually
但是不会经常这么做
know what the batch size is going to be beforehand.
因为提前不知道批次大小是多少
So, in general, you don't want to hard code that
通常 不能将此数字硬编码到
into your network or your tensors or anywhere.
网络 张量或任何位置
So, you do something like that.
不能这么做
With the images resized,
调整图像大小后
we can now pass it through our network.
现在可以传入网络中了
So to do this, you say model.forward.
为此 输入 model.forward
I'm going to put this into ps,
将这个放在 ps 中
so this just stands for probabilities.
ps 表示概率
So, forward pass our images,
输入 forward 传入图像
we're just going to take the first image.
获取第一个图像
That'll calculate our probabilities.
这样就可以计算概率
So now, I'm going to use dysfunction and the helper file
现在将使用这个函数 使用帮助程序文件
so helpers at the file I wrote that sits next to this and makes things easier and nicer.
我写的帮助程序可以使代码编写起来更轻松
So, I want to look at what our image is and then how our network classified it.
我要查看下图像是什么 网络是如何对其分类的
So, what is its prediction for the class.
类别预测是什么
So, here we're going to use image is zero.
输入 images[0]
So this time, we actually need to convert it back to a 28 by 28 image.
这次需要将其变回 28x28 的图像
So, I'm going to use view here.
在这里使用 view
So, view is basically like resizing except that it returns a new tensor.
view 和 resize 很像 但是它返回一个新的张量
So, resize it has an underscore at the end which means it's done in place,
这个 resize_ 有个下划线 表示原地操作
but view is the same as resizing,
view 和 resize reshape 相似
reshaping except it returns a new tensor.
但是它返回一个新的张量
So, we can pass in our image and when you pass
可以传入图像 传入概率分布
in probability distribution. I typed that wrong.
这里输错了
So, you can see here,
可以在这里看出
the image that we passed through our network is a seven and it's trying to make
我们传入网络中的图像是数字 7
some predictions but since the weights are random, we haven't trained it,
它尝试做出一些预测 但是因为权重是随机的 我们尚未训练网络
the network has no idea what the digit actually is, and so,
网络根本不知道该数字是什么
it's just giving us a random guesses where
它只是进行随机猜测
like all the probabilities are roughly the same.
所有概率都差不多
So, it's a uniform distribution right now because we haven't trained it yet.
现在是一个均匀分布 因为尚未训练网络
PyTorch provides a more convenient way for building a model called nn.Sequential.
PyTorch 提供了构建模型的更方便方式 叫做 nn.Sequential
So, I'll show you how to do this.
我将演示下如何使用此方式
First is want to define our hyper-parameters.
首先需要定义超参数
So, hyper parameters are parameters that define the architecture of your network,
超参数是用来定义网络架构的参数
and the parameters are the weights and biases themselves.
参数是权重和偏差本身
So, for instance, your input size is going to be 784.
例如 输入大小是 784
We can define the size of our hidden layers.
定义隐藏层的大小
So, this is would be 128 and 64 and then we can define the output size, is equal to 10.
输入 128 和 64 然后定义输出大小 等于 10
So with nn.Sequential we can say our model is this.
输入 model = nn.Sequential
Then basically, you just pass in the operations,
传入运算
the transformations, modules that you want to do.
即要执行的转换 模块
So, an nn.Linear input size and then hidden size zero. So that's the first module.
输入 nn.Linear(input_size, hidden_size[0] 这是第一个模块
Then we know we want this to go through yellow activation.
我们希望应用 ReLu 激活
So, nn.ReLU, and then the second Linear transformation and then another ReLU,
输入 nn.ReLU 然后是第二个线性转换 然后是另一个 ReLU
and finally, our output and then the softmax.
最终是输出 然后是 softmax
Then we print out the model,
输出模型
we see it's a sequential model and then we have this linear transformation,
可以看出它是一个序列模型 这里是线性转换
ReLU, linear transformation, ReLU,
ReLU 线性转换 ReLU
linear and then soft max.
线性转换 然后是 softmax
This is practically the same as the network that we built before,
基本上和之前构建的网络相同
except that it's much simpler to do and fewer lines of code.
但是创建起来更简单 代码行更少
Now we can do a forward pass through this and see that it's the same.
我们可以前向传播此网络 看到结果一样
So, we put another seven.
输入另一个数字 7
Since our network hasn't trained yet,
因为网络尚未训练
it doesn't know what the seven actually is.
不知道 7 到底什么样
Another cool thing you can do sequential is you can actually pass in in order to dict,
对于序列模型 有一个很酷的功能是可以传入 OrderedDict
in order to dictionary,
即有序字典
to name each of the layers in your sequential model.
用于命名序列模型中的每个层级
So, to get an order dict,
要获取 OrderedDict
do from collections "import OrderedDict.
输入 from collections import OrderedDict
Then we can build our model sequential.
然后可以构建序列模型
Then OrderedDict takes in a list of tuples that builds the dictionary keys and values.
OrderedDict 接受一个元组列表 用于构建字典键值
So here, the keys are going to be the names of
键将是层级名称
our layers and the values are going to be the operations themselves.
值将是运算本身
So, we can name our first layer FC1 for
例如 可以将第一个层级命名为 fc1
instance and given our normal linear thing and felt the rest of the network.
然后是正常的线性转换和后续网络运算
So, we call this one FC1 and then our first ReLU is relu1,
这个称为 fc1 第一个 ReLU 是 relu1
FC2, relu2 output softmax.
fc2 relu2 output softmax
So, one thing to note and remember that in a dictionary the keys have to be unique.
需要注意的一点是 在字典中 键必须是唯一的
So, you have to name this one relu1 or
将这个命名为 relu1 或任何其他名称
whatever and this ReLU activation has to have a different name,
这个 ReLU 激活函数必须具有不同的名称
and now we can look at our model.
现在看看我们的模型
So, you can see now each of our layers has a name attached to it.
可以看出 现在每个层级都有一个关联的名称
So, FC2 is this linear operation and we can actually get out FC2 here,
fc2 是这个线性运算 我们可以在这里获取 fc2
and so, there you go. They're named.
就这样 它们都有了名称
You can access them just like attributes
你可以访问它们
like we defined in the original network and go forward from there.
就像在原始网络中定义的属性一样 然后继续操作
So now, your turn to build a network.
现在该你来构建网络了
You can use any of these methods that I talked about here.
你可以使用我在本视频中讲解的任何方法
So what I want you to do is build a network to classify the images with
请构建一个分类 MNIST 图像的网络
three hidden layers and the first one should have 400 units second
必须有三个隐藏层 第一个隐藏层应该有 400 个单元
washed up 200 units and last one should have 100 units,
第二个应该有 200 个单元 最后一个应该有 100 个单元
and make sure you use ReLU activation functions on each of
确保在每个隐藏层上使用 ReLU 激活函数
them and softmax on the output layer.
在输出层使用 softmax
Here, you're not training the network yet,
暂时网络还没有训练
so it's not going to be able to make predictions.
因此无法做出预测
But in the next video notebook,
但是在下个视频 notebook 中
you'll learn how to do that,
你将学习这方面的知识
and so, you'll be able to train your network.
使你能够训练网络
See you in the next video. Cheers.
下个视频见 加油